Haverhill, Mass. First Congregational Church records, 1719-2012.
Congregational Library Archives
Haverhill, Mass. First Congregational Church records, 1719-2011.
RG5027
Congregational Library Archives
10.85 Cubic Feet
(11 boxes)
Haverhill was first settled by Puritans in 1640. Rev. John Ward was officially installed as the pastor of the First Parish in 1645 and the first meeting house was constructed in 1648. The second meeting house was completed in 1699 and the third was completed in 1766. In 1833 the First Parish became Unitarian and the Congregationalist dissenters formed the Independent Congregational Church and Society which was later renamed to the Centre Congregational Church and Society. In 1859 a large group of parishioners left the Centre Congregational Church to form the North Congregational Church. In 1940 the Centre and North Churches merged to form the First Congregational Church. In 1963 the North Parish Community Church merged into the First Congregational Church which simultaneously joined the United Church of Christ. In 2010 the First Congregational Church in Haverhill dissolved. This collection contains the administrative, financial, and important membership records of the First Parish Church, North Congregational Church, Centre Congregational Church, First Congregational Church, and North Parish Community Church.
Barnard, Edward, 1720-1774
Centre Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
First Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
First Parish Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
Independent Congregational Church and Society (Haverhill, Mass.)
North Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
North Parish Community Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by the First Congregational Church of Haverhill, Massachusetts, in May 2012; Accession 2012-02. Additional materials were transferred from the Haverhill Public Library in 2012; no accession number.
Accruals
Additional accruals are expected for this collection in the form of full-text transcription. There is no anticipated date for this accrual.
Historical Note
The land eventually called Haverhill was first settled by Puritans in 1640. In 1641 Rev. John Ward, from Haverhill England, came to the young settlement and became the first minister; the town was incorporated in1641 and named Haverhill after Ward's birthplace. The town lands were formally purchased from the Pentuckets in 1642. Rev. Ward was officially installed as the pastor of the First Parish in 1645 and the first meeting house was constructed in 1648. Rev. Ward served as the minister until his death in 1693. He was followed by Rev. Benjamin Rolfe and was installed in 1694. Construction on the second meeting house began in 1697 and was completed in 1699.
The town of Haverhill was separated into multiple parishes during the early eighteenth-century. In 1728 the town was divided into two parishes with the formation of the North Parish. The North Parish was transferred to Plaistow, New Hampshire in 1741 and the Rockingham Congregational Church was formed. In 1734 the town was divided yet again with the formation of the West Parish and the East Parish was formed in 1743. In 1748 a bell, imported from London, was installed in the First Parish church. The third meeting house was constructed 1766.
Rev. Dudley Phelps, a strict orthodox Congregationalist, was installed as the pastor of the First Parish in 1828. His strict orthodoxy became a point of contention and the parish dissolved its relation with Rev. Phelps in 1832. The First Parish, which kept the third meeting house, became a Unitarian church after the split. In 1833 the Independent Congregational Church and Society was formed with Rev. Joseph Whittelsey as its first minister. In 1840 the name was changed to Centre Congregational Church and Society. The new church originally worshipped at the Summer Street Church and Academy Hall until 1834 when a new church building was constructed. The church had a small separation in 1839 when seventeen members withdrew to form the Union Evangelical Church of Haverhill. That church was later renamed to the Winter Street Church. The winter street church was dissolved in 1860. By 1859 the Centre Congregational Church had grown significantly and it was decided that a portion of the parish would leave to form a new church in the north of Haverhill. In 1859 100 former members of the Centre Church formed the North Congregational Church. In 1891 some members of both the North and Centre Congregational Churches joined together to form the Union Congregational Church. The Union Congregational Church dissolved in 1932.
The first building of the North Congregational Church was completed in 1860. In the early twentieth-century, the building was renovated with Tiffany memorial windows. In 1929 the North Parish Community Church was formed after the dissolution of the Rockingham Congregational Church in Plaistow, New Hampshire. In 1940 the Centre Congregational Church and North Congregational Church merged to form the First Congregational Church in Haverhill which occupied the North Church building. In 1963 the North Parish Community Church merged into the First Congregational Church; at the same time the First Congregational Church joined the United Church of Christ. In 2010 the 1860 church building was sold and the First Congregational Church was formally dissolved.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the administrative, financial, and important membership records of the First Parish Church, North Congregational Church, Centre Congregational Church, First Congregational Church, and North Parish Community Church, all in Haverhill, Massachusetts. Included within this record collection are church meeting minutes, baptismal records, marriage records, death records, financial records, building records, photographs, correspondence, ledgers and record books, sermons, and valuable eighteenth-century membership records such as relations.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into five series. Each series contains the records of a single church. The North Congregational Church and First Congregational Church series have been further divided into several topical sub-series. Except where noted, series, sub-series, folders, and volumes have been arranged into chronological order. Generally, the contents of folders have largely remained in their original order.
Series 1: First Parish Church records, 1719-1756
Series 2: North Congregational Church records, 1824-2001
Sub-series 1: Church and society records, 1824-2001
Sub-series 2: North Church Sunday School records, 1859-1923
Sub-series 3: Financial and building records, 1859-1943
Sub-series 4: Church groups and committees, 1874-1926
Sub-series 5: Ministerial papers, 1894-1911
Series 3: Centre Congregational Church records, 1859-1942
Series 4: First Congregational Church records, 1900-2011
Sub-series 1: Image and audiovisual materials, 1900-2001
Sub-series 2: Church committees, societies, and groups, 1922-2010
Sub-series 3: Church and membership records, 1939-2011
Sub-series 4: Newsletters, 1946-2011
Sub-series 5: Financial and building records, 1947-2009
Sub-series 6: Sermons, 1959-2000
Series 5: North Parish Community Church records, 1924-1970
Technical Requirements
To access digital user's copies via online-interface, a java-enabled web browser is required. Internet Explorer 8.x and later, Firefox 5.x and later, Opera 12 and later, Safari 5.x and later, or any version of Google Chrome are recommended.
Videocassette materials require a videocassette player in order to play their content.
Related Materials
Artifacts and other materials from the First Congregational Church in Haverhill, Massachusetts, were donated to the Peabody Essex Museum in 2012.
Bibliography
Manual of the Centre Congregational Church in Haverhill, Mass. Haverhill: Chase Brothers, 1894.
Baptismal records.; Christian union.; Church bulletins.; Church discipline.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Church youth groups.; Marriage records.; Necrologies.; New England's Hidden Histories.; Pews and pew rights.; Sermons, American -- 20th century.; Sunday schools -- Records.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Worship programs.; Centre Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.); First Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.); First Parish Church (Haverhill, Mass.); Haverhill (Mass.) -- Church history.; North Congregational Church (Haverhill, Mass.); North Parish Community Church (Haverhill, Mass.)
- First Parish Church records, 1719 1756; 1719-1756; 9 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records created by the First Parish Church in Haverhill, Massachusetts. The majority of the records are relations, though disciplinary records and financial records are also included within the series.
  Arrangement
  The relations and disciplinary records have been artificially arranged into alphabetical order in order to facilitate the searching and retrieval of papers of specific individuals.
  - Relations A-B, 1719 1742; 1719-1742; 24 Items (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    These personal records were digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. An index of the digital reproductions is available to view online.
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters A through B.
    - Ames, Joseph, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - Ayer, Abigail, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
    - Ayer, Hannah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - Ayer, John, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 4)
    - Ayer, Nathaniel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 5)
    - Ayer, Rachel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 6)
    - Ayer, Ruth, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Ayer, Susannah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 8)
    - Badger, Hannah, 1742 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 9)
    - Badger, Joseph, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 10)
    - Bailey, Sarah, 1737 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 11)
    - Bayley, John, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 12)
    - Belknap, Abiah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 13)
    - Bond, Mercy, 1720 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 14)
    - Boynton, John, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 15)
    - Boynton, Joshua, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 16)
    - Bradley, Abigail, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 17)
    - Bradley, Daniel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 18)
    - Bradley, Daniel and Elizabeth, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 19)
    - Bradley, Elizabeth, 1738 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 20)
    - Bradley, Isaac, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 21)
    - Bradley, John, 1732 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 22)
    - Bradley, Joseph, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 23)
    - Buck, Ebenezer, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 24)
  - Relations C-D, 1719 1742; 1719-1742; 37 Items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Digital Copies
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters C through D.
    - Carlton, Edward, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - Clark, Abigail, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 2)
    - Clark, Edward, 1726 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 3)
    - Clark, Gift, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 4)
    - Clark, Samuel, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 5)
    - Clement, Abigail, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 6)
    - Clement, Hannah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 7)
    - Clement, John, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 8)
    - Clement, Jonathan, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 9)
    - Clement, Joseph, 1742 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 10)
    - Clement, Lydia, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 11)
    - Clement, Obadiah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 12)
    - Corlis, Elisabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 13)
    - Corlis, Rebecca, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 14)
    - Corlis, Ruth, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 15)
    - Crocker, Eleazar, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 16)
    - Currier, Abigail, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 17)
    - Currier, Elizabeth, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 18)
    - Currier, Grace, 1720 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 19)
    - Currier, Rueben, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 20)
    - Davis, Anna, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 21)
    - Davis, Deborah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 22)
    - Davis, Hannah, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 23)
    - Davis, Katherine, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 24)
    - Davis, Rebecca, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 25)
    - Davis, Samuel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 26)
    - Dodge, Martha, 1731 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 27)
    - Dow, Judith, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 28)
    - Dowe, Samuel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 29)
    - Dowe, Stephen, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 30)
    - Duston, Hannah, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 31)
    - Duston, Hannah, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 32)
    - Duston, Thomas, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 33)
    - Duston, Lydia, 1726 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 34)
    - Duston, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 35)
    - Duston, Mary, 1731 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 36)
    - Duston, Sarah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 37)
  - Relations E-G, 1719 1733; 1719-1733; 40 Items (Box 1, Folder 3)
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters E through G.
    - Eastman, Ebenezer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - Eastman, Mehetabel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - Eastman, Sarah, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 3)
    - Eastman, Sarah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
    - Eaton, Hannah, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 5)
    - Eaton, Hannah, 1733 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 6)
    - Eaton, Jeremiah, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 22)
    - Eaton, Mary, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 7)
    - Eaton, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 8)
    - Eaton, Mehetabel, 1726 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 9)
    - Ela, John, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 10)
    - Ela, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 11)
    - Ela, Sarah, 1742 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 12)
    - Ely, Abigail, 1720 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 13)
    - Emerson, Elizabeth, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 14)
    - Emerson, Hannah, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 15)
    - Emerson, Johnathan, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 16)
    - Emerson, Michael, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 17)
    - Ewing, William, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 18)
    - Ford, Hannah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 19)
    - Ford, Lydia, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 20)
    - Foster, David, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 21)
    - Gale, Benjamin, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 22)
    - Gile, Daniel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 23)
    - Gile, Ebenezer, 1733 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 24)
    - Gile, Elizabeth, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 25)
    - Gile, Ephraim, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 26)
    - Gile, Joanna, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 27)
    - Gile, Samuel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 28)
    - Gile, Sarah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 29)
    - Gourden, Elisabeth, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 30)
    - Gourden, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 31)
    - Greeley, Rachel, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 32)
    - Green, Elizabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 33)
    - Green. Martha, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 34)
    - Green, Peter, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 35)
    - Grele, Samuel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 36)
    - Grelee, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 37)
    - Griffing, Elisabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 38)
    - Guile, Ebenezer, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 39)
    - Gutterson, William, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 40)
  - Relations H-J, 1719 1738; 1719-1738; 37 Items (Box 1, Folder 4)
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters H through J.
    - Hassaltine, Hannah, 1738 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
    - Hassaltine, Judith, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Hassaltine, Mary, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)
    - Hassaltine, Nathaniel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 4)
    - Hastings, Elizabeth, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 5)
    - Hastings, Elizabeth, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 6)
    - Hastings, Robert, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 7)
    - Haynes, Sarah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 8)
    - Hazzen, Richard, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 9)
    - Hazzen, Sarah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 10)
    - Hazzen, Sarah, 1731 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 11)
    - Heath, Elisabeth, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 12)
    - Heath, Francis, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 13)
    - Heath, Joseph, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 14)
    - Heath, Lydia, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 15)
    - Heath, Phebe, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 16)
    - Herriman, Mary, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 17)
    - Herriman, Sarah, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 18)
    - Hinckley, Sarah, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 19)
    - Howe, Martha, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 20)
    - Hutchins, Hannah, 1726 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 21)
    - Hutchins, James, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 22)
    - Hutchins, Zerviah, 1733 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 23)
    - Ingals, Hannah, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 24)
    - Jonson, Abigail, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 25)
    - Jonson, John, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 26)
    - Jonson, Lydia, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 27)
    - Jonson, Mary, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 28)
    - Jonson, Mary, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 29)
    - Jonson, Mehetabel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 30)
    - Jonson, Rachel, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 31)
    - Jonson, Ruth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 32)
    - Jonson, Ruth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 33)
    - Jonson, Susanna, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 34)
    - Jonson, Susannah, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 35)
    - Jonson, Thomas, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 36)
    - Jonson, Thomas, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 37)
  - Relations K-O, 1717 1736; 1717-1736; 30 Items (Box 1, Folder 5)
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters K through O.
    - Kally, Samuel, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1)
    - Kelley, Richard, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 2)
    - Kimbal, Jemima, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 3)
    - Kimbal, Mary, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 4)
    - Kimbal, Richard, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 5)
    - Lad, Mary, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 6)
    - Little, Thomas, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 7)
    - Lovejoy, Hannah, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 8)
    - Main, Amos, 1717 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 9)
    - Main, Elizabeth, 1733 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 10)
    - Marsh, David, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 11)
    - Mash, Ephraim, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 12)
    - Mash, John, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 13)
    - Mash, Sarah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 14)
    - McHard, Margaret, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 15)
    - Merriel, Lucy, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 16)
    - Merril, Mary, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 17)
    - Merrill, Lydia, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 18)
    - Merrill, Mary, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 19)
    - Merrill, Nathan, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 20)
    - Merrill, Stephen, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 21)
    - Messer, John, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 22)
    - Messer, Mehetabel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 23)
    - Messer, Richard, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 24)
    - Messer, Sarah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 25)
    - Middleton, Dorothy, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 26)
    - Mingo, Thomas, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 27)
    - Mitchell, Andrew, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 28)
    - Mitchell, Susannah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 29)
    - Osgood, Lydia, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 30)
  - Relations P-R, 1719 1738; 1719-1738; 37 Items (Box 1, Folder 6)
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters P through R.
    - Page, Abiah, 1734 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 1)
    - Page, Cornelius, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 2)
    - Page, Edmund, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 3)
    - Page, Elizabeth, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 4)
    - Page, Elizabeth, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 5)
    - Page, Elizabeth, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 6)
    - Page, Hannah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 7)
    - Page, John, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 8)
    - Page, Joseph, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 9)
    - Page, Judith, 1720 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 10)
    - Page, Lewis, 1737 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 11)
    - Page, Lydia, 1737 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 12)
    - Page, Mary, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 13)
    - Page, Mary, 1735 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 14)
    - Page, Nathaniel, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 15)
    - Page, Susannah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 16)
    - Page, Timothy, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 17)
    - Parker, Bethia, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 18)
    - Patee, Elisabeth, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 19)
    - Patee, Sarah, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 20)
    - Pattee, Susan, 1732 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 21)
    - Pearson, Hannah, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 22)
    - Pearson, Hepzibah, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 22)
    - Pearson, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 22)
    - Peaslee, Abigail, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 23)
    - Peaslee, Elisabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 24)
    - Peaslee, Lydia, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 25)
    - Peaslee, Nathaniel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 26)
    - Peaslee, Rebecca, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 27)
    - Peaslee, Susanna, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 28)
    - Peasly, Judith, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 29)
    - Pecker, John, 1738 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 30)
    - Pike, Hanah, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 31)
    - Richards, Abigail, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 32)
    - Roberds, Daniel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 33)
    - Roberds, Ephraim, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 34)
    - Roberds, Hanah, 1721 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 35)
    - Roberds, Martha, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 36)
    - Rony, Abigail, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 37)
  - Relations S-W, 1719 1742; 1719-1742 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    This folder contains the personal records and relations of various early members of the First Parish Church. This folder contains the records of people whose last name began with the letters S through W.
    - Sanders, Abigail, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 1)
    - Sanders, Judith, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 2)
    - Sanders, Mary, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 3)
    - Sawyer, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 4)
    - Scribner, Elisabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 5)
    - Shepard, Hannah, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 6)
    - Shepard, Samuel, 1735 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 7)
    - Silver, Sarah, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 8)
    - Susanna, Silver, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 9)
    - Simons, Prudence, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 10)
    - Simons, Sarah, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 11)
    - Singletary, Sarah, 1723 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 12)
    - Smith, Abigail, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 13)
    - Smith, Samuel, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 14)
    - Smith, Sarah, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 15)
    - Smith, Susanna, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 16)
    - Stanley, Ruth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 17)
    - Staples, Abigail, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 18)
    - Staples, Elisabeth, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 19)
    - Staples, Elisabeth, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 20)
    - Staples, Thomas, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 21)
    - Sterry, Elisabeth, 1736 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 22)
    - Warner, Ann, 1733 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 23)
    - Watts, Dorothy, 1729 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 24)
    - Webster, Abigail, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 25)
    - Webster, John, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 26)
    - Webster, Stephen, 1732 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 27)